<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on ZecSec: Zcash Ecosystem Security</title><link>https://zecsec.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on ZecSec: Zcash Ecosystem Security</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 01:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zecsec.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Risk Analysis of Intel's SGX and Other TEEs</title><link>https://zecsec.com/posts/risk-analysis-of-intel-sgx-and-other-tees/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 01:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://zecsec.com/posts/risk-analysis-of-intel-sgx-and-other-tees/</guid><description>Intel&amp;rsquo;s Software Guard eXtensions (SGX) is a Trusted Execution Environment (TEE) technology built into some Intel CPUs. It is a special mode of operation that the processor can be put into that intends to allow for integrity-protected and confidentiality-protected processing, even under the assumption that the machine is fully compromised (i.e. the attacker has root access).
Using cryptographic keys baked into the sillicon, SGX intends to allow the processor to remotely &amp;ldquo;attest&amp;rdquo; to its secure execution state, so that clients can be assured that they are interacting with safe code (the &amp;ldquo;enclave&amp;rdquo;) and can provide secrets to that code without them being vulnerable to theft even by root users of the system.</description></item><item><title>Making Zcash Light Wallets Faster and More Private</title><link>https://zecsec.com/posts/making-zcash-light-wallets-faster-and-more-private/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 01:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://zecsec.com/posts/making-zcash-light-wallets-faster-and-more-private/</guid><description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to sketch changes to the Zcash protocol that would allow light wallets to be both much faster and more private than they currently are. By writing this post, I hope to start a discussion about how we can pragmatically fix the privacy leaks in the current light wallet protocol and at the same time vastly improve light wallet performance.
Warning: There are almost certainly security bugs in the protocol described below that I haven&amp;rsquo;t caught, so please don&amp;rsquo;t implement this without careful thought!</description></item><item><title>ZecSec's Q4 2022 Transparency Report</title><link>https://zecsec.com/posts/2022-q4-transparency-report/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 01:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://zecsec.com/posts/2022-q4-transparency-report/</guid><description>In order to ensure accountability and to help the Zcash community understand how its funds are being spent, the ZecSec project will be posting quarterly transparency reports.
Note that some of these reports may be delayed, and some information may be redacted, in order to prevent the disclosure of unresolved security bugs.
The currently-approved grant allows me to bill $1000 USD per day, up to a maximum of $17,000 per month, up to 12 total months.</description></item><item><title>ZecSec Roadmap for 2023</title><link>https://zecsec.com/posts/zecsec-roadmap-for-2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 11:08:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://zecsec.com/posts/zecsec-roadmap-for-2023/</guid><description>Happy New Year Zcash!
For me, the days leading up to the new year are always a time of reflection and planning. In that spirit, I&amp;rsquo;ve laid out a tentative roadmap for the ZecSec project in 2023.
Upcoming Audits 1. Lightwalletd All Zcash light wallets rely on the lightwalletd project to obtain transaction information and to broadcast transactions to the network. Despite its central importance to the Zcash ecosystem, it has never been subjected to a third-party audit.</description></item><item><title>YWallet Audit Results Published</title><link>https://zecsec.com/posts/ywallet-audit-published/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 07:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://zecsec.com/posts/ywallet-audit-published/</guid><description>In October of last year, I reviewed YWallet for security and privacy issues. This was the first audit I performed for the Zcash Ecosystem Security grant.
Today, the final report is being made available to the Zcash community at the link below.
The audit found one high-severity issue, two medium-severity issues, and several low-severity issues. At this point in time, all issues have been remediated or deemed to be safe to de-prioritize relative to other work.</description></item><item><title>Security Audit Process</title><link>https://zecsec.com/posts/security-audit-process/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 07:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://zecsec.com/posts/security-audit-process/</guid><description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to shed light on the process I follow to find bugs in my audits of Zcash ecosystem software. Hopefully, this will be useful to you if you are looking to understand more about how audits work or even learning how to audit software yourself.
The process I&amp;rsquo;m describing here should not be taken as gospel. Different security auditors follow different processes, and I often deviate from this process significantly to tailor my audits to the specific projects I am helping.</description></item><item><title>Scalable Private Money Needs Scalable Anonymous Messaging</title><link>https://zecsec.com/posts/scalable-private-money-needs-scalable-private-messaging/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 19:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://zecsec.com/posts/scalable-private-money-needs-scalable-private-messaging/</guid><description>In this post I’m going to argue that any scalable private Internet money system will need to rely on an equally-scalable and equally-private anonymous messaging system.
Ultimately, I will argue that the best approach to scaling private money is to directly and explicitly build a scalable anonymous communication system, rather than proceeding through a series of ad-hoc improvements to current designs.
Backstory The performance of Zcash mobile wallets has been degraded massively; this was caused by a huge increase in private transaction load on the network.</description></item><item><title>October Update: Ywallet audited, and what's next?</title><link>https://zecsec.com/posts/october-update/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 08:13:14 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://zecsec.com/posts/october-update/</guid><description>Hi Zcash fans! It&amp;rsquo;s time for the first monthly update on the Zcash Ecosystem Security grant. This October, we saw the completion of a full security audit of Ywallet.
Ywallet&amp;rsquo;s fast scanning algorithm makes it an attractive option for users facing long delays due to the recent high usage of the Zcash blockchain. It had also received the least security review among the Zcash wallets, so we decided to prioritize it as the first project to be audited for this grant.</description></item><item><title>Hello, World!</title><link>https://zecsec.com/posts/my-first-post/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 08:22:29 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://zecsec.com/posts/my-first-post/</guid><description>Hi!
This is where I will be posting be posting updates on the Zcash Ecosystem Security grant project!</description></item></channel></rss>